<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Lambda Continuum</title>
    <link>https://lambdacontinuum.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Lambda Continuum</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 17:59:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://lambdacontinuum.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Divine Agency Without Failure</title>
      <link>https://lambdacontinuum.github.io/posts/divine-agency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 17:59:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lambdacontinuum.github.io/posts/divine-agency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Philosophy of Religion has recently seen a surge of popularity in philosophy circles online, so I’ve decided to throw my hat in the ring. Here’s an argument against God being an agent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wittgenstein makes an interesting distinction. He distinguishes viewing intentions as mere mental processes from viewing intentions in terms of their fulfillment. For the latter, the idea here is that elements in the world can be &lt;strong&gt;taken&lt;/strong&gt; to be in accord with such intentional states. Fulfillment conveys something that is normative in some minimal sense, leading us to think the very idea of intention is a normative idea. The general gist is that intentional states seem like the types of states that have standards by which one could be in accord or out of accord with them. Consider the cases of belief and desire. Suppose an agent believes that it’s raining outside, believes that an umbrella will protect them from the rain, and desires not to be wet. If such an agent were to walk outside without taking their umbrella, they’d be out of accord with their very own intentional states. The observation here is that intentional states seem to generate ideals of norm or correctness, and these norms are such that one could be in accord with or fail to accord with them. We can assess an agent’s actions as correct or incorrect by the light of the norms generated by their intentions. Thus, normativity is constitutive of intentional states.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contra Standard Deontic LOgic</title>
      <link>https://lambdacontinuum.github.io/posts/contra-sdl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 17:57:25 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lambdacontinuum.github.io/posts/contra-sdl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I’ve started publishing again, I decided to begin with a re-write of an old article titled something alon&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bengt Hansson introduced the term &lt;em&gt;Standard Deontic Logic&lt;/em&gt; (referred to as SDL from here on) to denote deontic&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ℐ represents the set of deontically perfect worlds. Sentences valid in such a model coincide with the sentences&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Op → &lt;del&gt;O&lt;/del&gt;p,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Op∧Oq ↔ O(p∧q),&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;O(p∨q).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The second axiom is equivalent to the combination of:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
